片名：天空上尉与明日世界
乘客们请注意，我们准备着陆
Attention. Please prepare
for docking procedure.
准备就绪
年青人
你能帮我送个信吗？
好的，瓦格斯博士
交给沃特・詹宁斯博士
我立刻去，博士，不会有问题的
“詹宁斯博士，我被跟踪了，你必须保护他们
再见了，朋友――瓦格斯”
（“乔治・瓦格斯博士”名字被划掉）
记事报
兴登堡三号飞艇飞临纽约
泊于帝国大厦
“警方搜寻失踪的科学家，乔治・瓦格斯教授”
――波莉・帕金斯
波莉・帕金斯办公室
“科学家失踪”
帕金斯小姐，这有你的包裹
There's a package for you,
Miss Perkins.
上面没有署名
They didn't leave a name.
- 他们说这个很重要
- 谢谢
- Said it was important.
- Thank you.
伊萨克・牛顿，
现代哲学中的数学原理
“我知道谁是下一个
今晚6点单独来见我！”
我不想让你卷进这件事情里去
I don't like this business
you're getting yourself into.
我没事的，佩利先生
你知道我很小心的
I'll be just fine, Mr. Paley.
You know what a careful girl I am.
我苦口婆心，你就是听不进去
I move my mouth, words come out,
you don't hear.
- 我看电影要迟到了
- 我不喜欢你对着我笑
- I'm late for a movie.
- I don't like it when you smile at me.
你不喜欢我笑吗？
You don't like my smile?
我是不喜欢你笑里藏刀
I don't like what's behind it.
听着，波莉，六个科学家失踪了
很可能已经死了
Listen, Polly, six scientists are missing,
probably dead.
调查那件事情的人都很危险
我不想你也卷进去
Somebody out there means business.
I don't want you in the middle of it.
仅仅只是去看一部电影，佩利先生
It's only a movie, Mr. Paley.
我给你带些爆米花
I'll bring you some popcorn.
图图，我感觉我们好像不在堪萨斯
Toto, I have a feeling
we're not in Kansas anymore.
我们肯定在彩虹上
We must be over the rainbow.
这是你寄给我的？
You sent me this?
你是谁？
Who are you?
- 这一切究竟是怎么回事
- 博士
- What's this all about, Mr...?
- Doctor.
沃特・詹宁斯博士，我是一个化学家
Dr. Walter Jennings.
I'm a research chemist.
我是研究核酸辐射的
I specialize in nucleic-acid emissions.
就是蛋白质分子间的键...
The bonding enzymes
in proteus molecules which--
那些失踪的科学家
你说你知道谁是下一个
The missing scientists.
You said you knew who was next.
是的，我
Yes, l--
我们见面的时间到了，博士
I have a deadline to meet, doctor.
我是被选中的参加这个秘密试验的
七个科学家中的一个
I was one of seven scientists
chosen to serve in a secret facility
在一战之前驻扎在柏林城外
stationed outside of Berlin
before the start of the First World War.
它被称作Einheit Elf“11单元”
It was known only as Einheit Elf,
"Unit 1 1."
我们发过誓，
永远不在实验室之外的地方谈论它
We agreed never to discuss
what went on behind those doors.
在那里，我们所做的都是些
The things we were made
to do there...
可怕的事情
Terrible things.
- 我不该来的
- 现在我确信我们不在堪萨斯了
- I shouldn't have come.
- Now I know we're not in Kansas.
你是一个好女巫还是一个坏女巫？
Are you a good witch
or a bad witch?
博士，你说你知道谁是下一个
Doctor, you said you knew
who was next.
是的
Yes.
你没发现吗？
Don't you see?
- 只剩下最后一个了
- 谁？他是谁，博士
- There is only one left.
- Who? Who is it, doctor?
我
Me.
他来抓我了
He's coming for me.
谁？谁来了？
Who? Who's coming?
托滕可夫
Totenkopf.
It's Totenkopf.
瞧那
There!
所有市民，请注意
All citizens, attention.
纽约市必须马上疏散
New York City
must be evacuated at once.
请大家有秩序撤到河东路
Proceed in an orderly manner
to the East River Drive.
所有休息的警察和消防队员
All members of the police and fire
department on leave or off duty
必须马上向上级报道
shall report immediately to their
precincts or company command.
这很紧急
This is urgent.
- 佩利编辑
- 佩利先生，是我，波莉
- Editor Paley.
- Mr. Paley, it's me, Polly.
发生什么事了？他们要求撤离市中心
What's going on? They're calling
for midtown to evacuate.
听着，佩利先生
我没有时间了
Listen, Mr. Paley,
I don't have much time.
我要你搜集
所有关于沃特・詹宁斯博士的资料
I need you to dig up anything you can
on a Dr. Walter Jennings
以及一个叫托滕可夫的人
and someone named Totenkopf.
地址，电话号码，所有你可以找到的
这很重要
An address, a phone number,
anything you can find. It's important.
托滕可夫是谁？
Totenkopf. Who is he?
他可能与失踪的科学家有关
He may have something to do
with the missing scientists.
尽快
Quick as you can.
波莉 ，听我说
我要你离开这里
Polly, listen to me.
I want you to get out of there.
我想你挂上电话，关上你的记事本
I want you to put the phone down,
close your notepad
离开那个鬼地方
and get the hell out of there.
等等
Wait a minute.
我看见帕利赛饭店上空有一些东西
I can see something now coming
into sight above the Palisades.
他们正在穿越第六大街
They're crossing Sixth Avenue.
第五大街
Fifth Avenue.
他们在一百码
他们在一百码之外
They're a hundred--
They're a hundred yards away.
波莉，波莉！
Polly. Polly!
天啊
Oh, my God.
波莉！
Polly!
别跑！回来！
Stop! Come back!
开火！
Fire!
离开这儿！
Get out of here!
他们已经突破了防线
要求支援
They've broken through the perimeter.
Send reinforcements.
把你所有的部队都派来
Send everything you've got!
紧急状况协议90206
呼叫天空上尉，请回答，天空上尉
Emergency protocol 90206. Calling
Sky Captain. Come in, Sky Captain.
重复，呼叫天空上尉
请回答，天空上尉
Repeat. Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
这是紧急状况，90206
This is an emergency
protocol, 90206.
呼叫天空上尉
天空上尉，你听到了吗？
Calling Sky Captain.
Sky Captain, do you read?
呼叫天空上尉
请回答，天空上尉
Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
这是紧急状况，90206
This is an emergency
protocol, 90206.
呼叫天空上尉
天空上尉，你听到没有
Calling Sky Captain.
Sky Captain, do you read?
重复，呼叫天空上尉
请回答，天空上尉
Repeat. Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
我是天空上尉，我正赶来
This is Sky Captain. I'm on my way.
波莉
Polly.
约瑟夫
Joe.
袭击的进一步情况接踵而至
Further details of the attack
continue to pour in.
城市中心的无线通讯已经中断
The central portion of the city is
blacked out from radio communication
因为能源线被损坏以及电力系统故障
due to damaged power lines
and electrical failure.
来自英国、法国、德国的电报
Cables received from English, French
and German news agencies
证实了收到袭击的不仅仅只是这个城市
now confirm the attack
was not limited to the city.
BBC正在报告一家在纽伦堡的钢铁厂
The BBC is reporting
that a steel mill in Nuremberg
事实上已被挖空
was virtually excavated
目击者把它形容成一种机械龙卷风
by what witnesses describe
as a mechanized tornado.
巴黎和马德里通讯社
谈及奇怪的挖掘机器
News agencies in Paris and Madrid
speak of strange burrowing machines
正浮出地面
rising from the ground,
开采整个地区的煤炭和石油
robbing entire communities
of their coal and oil reserves.
同时，全球的军队都高度警戒
Meanwhile, with military resources
stretched thin across the globe,
各国元首再一次呼吁
world leaders
must once again call upon
天空上尉和他的精英们
the elite mercenary forces
of Sky Captain and his army-for-hire
来解开这些神秘事件的真相
to uncover the meaning
of these mysterious events.
德克斯在哪？
Where's Dex?
天啊
Shazam.
我以为你说的这个东西很大
可以把它给我吗？
I thought you said this thing was big.
Can I have it?
如果你查出它从哪儿来
我就买一个做你的圣诞礼物
You find out where it came from,
and I'll buy you one for Christmas.
哦，我要给你看些东西
Oh, I need to show you something.
在这种机器第一次出现之前
我记录下这个信号
I recorded this signal just before
the first machine appeared.
直到我重放它才想到些事情
I didn't think anything of it
until I played it back.
- 摩尔斯代码
- 我开始也是这么想的
- Morse code?
- See, that's what I thought at first,
但是要比这更复杂
but the syntax
is more complex than that.
在低频部份隐藏了载波
There's a sub-carrier hidden
in the lower frequency.
我想这是用来控制它们的
I think it's being used
to control them.
如果可以再出现，你可以跟踪它吗？
If it shows up again,
could you track it?
我可以试试
I can try, yeah.
- 很好，德克斯
- 谢谢
- Good boy, Dex.
- Thanks.
那么看看你能用这个干些什么
In the meantime,
see what you can do with that thing.
找出是什么让它运作的
Find out what makes it tick.
- 你不介意吧？
- 当然
- You don't mind, do you?
- I don't mind.
我想知道它从哪儿来
德克斯，是谁送过来的
I wanna know where it comes from,
Dex. Who sent it here.
转换到坐标图西南69东49
Switch to map coordinate
69 SW by 49 E.
胃痛？
Tummy ache?
你好吗,约瑟夫？
How you been, Joe?
- 想我吗？
- 出去
- Miss me?
- Get out.
很好，很高兴再次见到你
Well, it's nice to see you too.
德克斯说你可能心情不好
Dex said you might be in a mood.
德克斯？
Dex?
进来
Get in here!
已经三年了，约瑟夫
你现在生我气了，对吧？
It's been three years, Joe.
You're not still mad at me, are you?
还记得我们当初为什么吵架吗？
Can't even remember
what we were fighting about.
你弄坏了我的飞机
You sabotaged my plane.
是的
Right.
因为你 我在满洲的监狱呆了6个月
I spent six months in a Manchurian
slave camp because of you.
- 他们想切断我的手指。
- 约瑟夫
- They were gonna cut off my fingers.
- Joe,
上一次，我没有弄坏你那该死的飞机
for the last time, I didn't sabotage
your damn airplane.
你那样只是为了得到东条英机的照片
All so you could get a photograph
of Tojo Hideki
在他的的浴衣里，记得吗？
in his bathrobe, remember?
是的，我开始认为
You know, I'm starting to think
你编造了这个弄坏飞机的谣言
that you've invented
this whole sabotage nonsense
来瞒着我
to cover the fact that
you were running around on me
和你的神秘女孩卿卿我我
那个时候我们都在南京
with your little mystery girl
the whole time we were in Nanjing.
没有的事
都是你自己瞎想的
Never happened.
All in your imagination.
她是谁，约瑟夫？
Who was she, Joe?
- 她叫什么？
- 够了
- What was her name?
- That's enough.
你想干吗？
What are you gonna do?
杀了我吗？
Shoot me?
太好了，我们都到齐了
Oh, great. We all made up.
见到你很荣幸，波莉
It's been a pleasure, Polly.
让我们像10年前那样
护送帕金斯小姐离开基地，德克斯
Let's do it again in ten years.
Escort Miss Perkins off the base, Dex.
如果她反抗，就开枪
If she resists, shoot her.
- 嘿，波莉
- 嘿，德克斯
- Hi, Polly.
- Hi, Dex.
- 我准备...
- 没事，我知道
- I gotta...
- It's okay, hon, I know.
好的
Okay.
还有，我猜你对这个可能没兴趣吧
It's just as well. I guess you wouldn't
have been interested in this, anyway.
- 你从那儿得到那个？
- 那儿还有更多这样的东西
- Where did you get that?
- There's more where this came from.
很多
Lots more.
- 我要那个图纸，波莉
- 我要这个新闻，约瑟夫
- I want that blueprint, Polly.
- I want this story, Joe.
你要帮助我得到它
And you're gonna help me get it.
可能我们应该给她看看，上尉
或许她能提供帮助
Maybe we should show her, Cap.
Maybe she can help.
给我看什么
Show me what?
天啊，这是什么？
My God. What is this?
你们从哪弄来的？
Where do they come from?
三年前它们在一个偏远地区出现
They started appearing three years ago
in remote areas.
我们保守这个秘密至今
We managed to keep it a secret
until now.
它们来之前没有任何征兆
拿走它们想要的东西
They show up without warning,
they take what they need,
接着它们消失的无影无踪
and then they disappear
without a trace.
三年了，我仍然不知道它们想要什么
Three years and we still can't explain
what they want
或谁派它们来的
or who's sending them here.
今天有一个人和我会面
一个科学家
A man came to see me today,
a scientist.
他很害怕
说有人要抓他
He was terrified.
Said someone was coming for him.
我问他在害怕谁
他一直重复一个名字：
I asked him who he was so afraid of,
and he repeated one name:
托滕可夫
Totenkopf.
他说的时候脸色苍白
He nearly went white
when he said it.
托滕可夫，他是谁？
Totenkopf, who is he?
他是个神秘的人
He's the invisible man.
我已经查看了所有馆藏记录两次
希望能查出点什么
I've been through every library record
twice looking for anything.
我已经联系了从巴黎到曼谷
所有我所能联系的人
I've called every contact I have
from Paris to Bangkok.
这是我唯一知道的
This is the only thing I could dig up.
他掌管着柏林郊外的一些秘密科学基地
He ran some kind of secret
science unit outside of Berlin
在第一次世界大战之前
before the start of World War l.
一些叫做11单元的东西
Something called Unit 1 1.
上次别人提到他的名字
已经是三十多年前了
It's been more than 30 years
since anyone has spoken his name.
直到今天才又有人提起
Until today.
看看他用的徽章
Note the insignia he used
for the unit.
标记在所有这些机器上
It matches the markings
on all of these machines.
那个科学家，他现在在哪？
The scientist, where is he now?
我们一起干吧，约瑟夫？
We're in this together, right, Joe?
直到我同意前任何事都不可以公开
你不能写一句话
Nothing gets published until I say so.
You don't write a sentence
或者在没有得到我的同意下照相，懂了吗？
or take a photograph without
asking me first. Understood?
知道了
Understood.
什么？
What?
我想你
I missed you.
另外，谢谢你今天救了我
Thanks for saving my life today,
by the way.
是你跌倒在那吗？
Were you down there?
你也想我
真好
You missed me too. How nice.
就是这了
这就是詹宁斯的实验室
This is it. This is Jennings' lab.
詹宁斯博士？我是波莉・帕金斯
Dr. Jennings? It's Polly Perkins.
詹宁斯博士
Dr. Jennings!
它锁上了
It's locked.
那里有个窗户
That window there.
我可能可以从那个窗户进去
I may be able to get in
through that window
如果我有一条绳子...
if I can attach a line...
开了
It's open.
我们来晚了
有人已经来过了
We're too late.
Someone beat us here.
好了，波莉
All right, Polly...
别在玩花样了
到底发生了什么？
...no more games.
What the hell is going on?
我还希望你告诉我呢
I was hoping you could tell me.
詹宁斯博士
Dr. Jennings!
你必须阻止他！
You must stop him!
呆在这儿
Stay here.
别动！
Stop!
我不想伤害你
I don't wanna hurt you.
- 帕金斯小姐
- 我在这，博士
- Miss Perkins.
- I'm here, doctor.
- 我去找人来帮你
- 答应我
- I'm going to get you some help.
- You must promise.
如果托滕可夫找到它们，倒计时就会开始
If Totenkopf finds them,
the countdown will begin.
- 这个世界就会毁灭
- 我不明白，博士，找什么？
- This world shall end.
- I don't understand, doctor. Find what?
答应我
Promise.
他死了
He's dead.
我想我找到了些东西
I think I found something.
今天早上在电影院里詹宁斯博士就带着这个
Dr. Jennings had this with him
this morning at the theater.
- 我最好回到基地去
- 我和你一起去
- I'd better get back to the base.
- I'm coming with you.
当然
Of course you are.
雷达侦察到有物体以500哩/小时的速度移动
Reconnaissance picked up something
on radar traveling at over 500 knots
直接向我们这儿过来了
and coming straight for us.
- 它们到我们这儿还有多久？
- 看那
- How long before they reach us?
- There!
准备好我的飞机，我要起飞了
Get my plane ready. I'm going up.
- 你在干什么？
- 我和你一起去
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming with you.
别傻了，记得上次你和我一起飞的时候
发生了什么吗
Don't be stupid. Remember what
happened last time you flew with me?
- 我们有一个协议
- 这不是游戏，波莉
- We had a deal.
- This is not a game, Polly.
- 人们就要死了
- 你别想扔下我，约瑟夫
- People are gonna die.
- You are not leaving me, Joe.
这次不行，这是我的新闻
并且我们有协议！
Not this time. This is my story,
and we had a deal!
快跑，快跑，快跑
Go, go, go!
上来
Get in.
就是你
There you are.
- 上尉，这里是德克斯，你能听到吗？
- 别挂断，德克斯，我有些事要先处理
- Cap, this is Dex, do you read me?
- Hang on, Dex, I'm a little busy.
说吧，德克斯
Come in, Dex.
听着，不管你作什么，不要开枪！
Look, whatever you do, don't shoot!
- 好的
- 你开枪了，是不是？
- Okay.
- You shot it, didn't you?
- 是的
- 听着，上尉
- Yes.
- Listen, Cap,
信号来自其中一台飞机
the signal's coming
from one of those machines.
你必须让它们保持完整
You gotta keep them
in one piece.
是哪台机器，德克斯？
Which machine is it, Dex?
这没法说
可能是其中任何一台
There's no way of telling.
It could be any one of them.
我想我找到它了，德克斯
I think I found it, Dex.
- 等等，上尉，我失去信号了
- 它正前往城市
- Wait, Cap, I'm losing the signal.
- It's heading for the city.
别让它跑了，你把信号反馈给我
Don't let it get away. I need you
to bounce that signal back to me.
如果现在让它跑了，
我们可能再也追不到了
If we lose it now,
we may never get it back.
告诉我什么时候你发现的，德克斯
You let me know when
you've got something, Dex.
我会让你知道的
完毕
I'll let you know. Out.
好了，我要一个全光谱扫描仪
扫描所有进来的信号
All right, I want a full-spectrum sweep
of every incoming signal.
放大每一个不同的频率周期
并把它们发送给我
Amplify any variant frequency cycle
and route them to me.
它们回到发电机那里了
They've come back
for the generators.
这些家伙是谁？
Who is this guy?
- 你还好吧？
- 没事
- You okay?
- Great.
如果你需要
这里有一瓶镁氧奶在座位下
There's a bottle of Milk of Magnesia
under the seat if you need it.
- 我没事
- 你看起来不是很好
- I'm fine.
- You don't look so good.
小心
Pull up!
- 约瑟夫！
- 我看见它了！
- Joe!
- I see it!
它要跑了
It's getting away.
- 我失去了信号，上尉
- 我会找到它的，德克斯，别急
- I lost the signal, Cap.
- I'll find him, Dex. Sit tight.
- 去左边
- 往后坐，波莉
- Go left.
- Sit back, Polly.
这里有一条捷径去百老汇
你可以在第42号街跟住它
There's a shortcut down Broadway.
You can catch him on 42nd Street.
这些街道我如数家珍
去左边！
I know these streets like the back
of my hand. Go left!
嗨
Hey!
好的，好的，现在直走
Okay, okay, now go straight.
- 不，不，不，走右边！
- 什么时候？
- No, no, no, go right!
- When?
回那里
Back there.
下次我需要你早一点的提示
I could use a little more warning
next time.
走左边！
Go left!
告诉我你发现了什么，德克斯
Tell me you got something, Dex.
我们这儿很不爽
We're getting clobbered up here.
我这里也不舒服，上尉
坚持住，我很快就能找到了
It's no picnic down here either, Cap.
Hang in there, I've almost got it.
约瑟夫！
Joe!
德克斯！我们不能坚持多久了！
Dex! We can't hold them off
any longer!
- 我就快找到了
- 我们必须撤退了！
- I'm almost there.
- We have to evacuate now!
你们先走
我随后而来
Go ahead without me.
I'm right behind you.
- 漂亮
- 好的，在药店转左
- Lovely.
- Okay, turn left at the drugstore.
- 再左
- 我们在绕圈
- Left again.
- We're going around in circles.
你相信我行吗？转左！
Will you just trust me? Go left!
- 这是一个死胡同
- 应该可以走出去的啊
- It's a dead end.
- That's not supposed to be there.
这是死胡同！
It's a dead end!
这里没有路可以出去！
There's no way out!
哦，畜生们
Oh, bugger.
约瑟夫！
Joe!
- 领头的在那里
- 捷径
- There's the lead ship.
- Shortcut!
是我带的路，不是吗？
I got us here, didn't l?
- 德克斯，德克斯！
- 还要30秒，上尉，我需要30秒
- Dex. Dex!
- Thirty seconds, Cap, that's all I need.
- 30秒
- 或多或少
- Thirty seconds.
- Plus or minus.
听着，我会试着把它们带到水面上
多耗点时间，完毕
Listen, I'll try and take them out over
the water, buy us some time. Over.
你还想和我一起来吗？
Still glad you came?
约瑟夫，我找到它了！约瑟夫！
Joe, I found it! Joe!
德克斯,告诉我
它在哪里？
Dex, come in. Where is it?
告诉我，德克斯
你在那儿吗？德克斯？
Come in, Dex. Are you there? Dex?
德克斯，你听到没有？
Dex, do you read me?
德克斯，你还在吗？
Dex, are you there?
我没时间和它们绕了
I can't outrun them much longer.
坚持住
Hold on.
约瑟夫，你在干什么？
你在往下直坠
Joe, what are you doing?
You're heading straight down!
- 你会杀了我们的！
- 我知道我在作什么，坚持住
- You're gonna kill us!
- I know what I'm doing. Just hold on.
我们速度太快了
我们不可能成功的
We're going too fast.
We're not gonna make it.
约瑟夫，你必须上升
Joe, you have to pull up!
上升！
Pull up!
- 我们在水下走
- 德克斯做了这个装置
- We went underwater.
- Dex rigged it up.
从他的一本连环画里上得来的想法
Got the idea from one
of his comic books.
你是说，你一直都知道
You mean, you knew this
the whole time,
而且你让我以为我们将坠机？
and you let me think
we were gonna crash?
我以为我们要死了！
你应该告诉我的！
I thought we were gonna die!
You should have said something!
瞧，波莉，是你要来的
不是我让你来的
Look, Polly, it was your idea
to tag along, not mine.
如果你受不了，
那就不是我的问题了
If you can't take it,
that's not my fault.
我受的了
Oh, I can take it.
- 我能忍受你的一切
- 好的
- I can take anything you dish out.
- Good.
因为那不算什么
Because that was nothing.
德克斯，你在吗
能听见我吗？
Dex, come in. Do you read me?
你能听见我吗，德克斯？重复
Do you read me, Dex? Copy.
德克斯！
Dex!
德克斯
Dex.
它们到处都是
They're everywhere.
约瑟夫，小心！
Joe, look out!
德克斯！
Dex!
托滕可夫为什么要这样做？
Why would Totenkopf do this?
为什么抓走德克斯？
这没有任何意义
Why Dex?
It doesn't make any sense.
他在找什么
He was looking for something.
德克斯说他找到信号从哪儿发射过来的了
Dex said he knew where
the transmission was coming from.
他一定很接近了
He must have got too close.
- 他想告诉我什么
- 约瑟夫
- He was trying to tell me something--
- Joe.
干得好，德克斯
Good boy, Dex.
这些日记属于瓦格斯博士的
These journals belong to Dr. Vargas.
在他消失之前
他一定已经交给了詹宁斯博士
He must have passed them on to
Dr. Jennings before his disappearance.
- 我的天
- 什么？
- My God.
- What?
在托滕可夫12岁的时候
他获得了第一个专利
"Totenkopf was awarded his first
patent when he was 1 2 years old.
17岁时，他已经拿到了两个博士学位
By 1 7, he had already received
two doctorates
是他们那个时代最受关注的人
and was one of the most highly
regarded minds of his day.
他消失后一年
可怕的谣言开始流传开来
One year after his disappearance,
ominous rumors began circulating.
说托滕可夫已经开始制造
Whispers that Totenkopf
had begun work
一个毁灭世界的黑暗设施
on what was darkly hinted
to be a doomsday device.
寻找他的任务一个个的失败了
Efforts to locate him
have consistently failed,
直到今天他的行踪仍是一个谜
and to this day, his whereabouts
remain a mystery.
对他的同伴也了解甚少
Even less is known
about his companion,
一个控制机器的杀手
an assassin who controls
his machines."
她就是抓德克斯的人
She's the one who took Dex.
还有什么？
What else?
这是11单元供给记录
These are Unit 1 1 supply logs.
这些都是他用他的机器收集的
This is everything he's used
his machines to collect
在最后的三年里，包括城市的发电机
for the last three years,
including generators from the city.
它读起来就像全世界的购物清单
It reads like a shopping list
from all over the world.
你究竟在做什么呢，博士？
What have you been up to, doctor?
没事的，约瑟夫
德克斯能照顾好他自己的
It'll be all right, Joe.
Dex can look after himself.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
我的老朋友约瑟夫
My old friend Joe.
- 很高兴再看到你
- 我也一样，卡吉
- So glad to see you again.
- It's good to see you too, Kaji.
很高兴再看到你
我也一样，卡吉
- So glad to see you again.
- It's good to see you too, Kaji.
这是 波莉・帕金斯
她将和我们一起去
This is Polly Perkins.
She'll be coming with us.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
- 卡吉，你拿到我需要的地图了吗？
- 是的，它们在里面
- Kaji, did you get the maps I needed?
- Yeah, they're inside.
你有没有我要的那些东西
Did you get a little something
for me?
当然，三箱
如你所需
Of course. Three cases,
just like you asked.
维也纳香肠
我的天，期盼的太久了
Vienna sausages.
My God, it's been so long.
卡吉，你的西藏语如何？
Kaji, how's your Tibetan?
冷的时候乳头都能冻硬
过来，我给你看地图
Come, I'll show you the maps.
- 你对他了解多少？
- 卡吉？
- How well do you know him?
- Kaji?
他是罗马兵团老侦察兵，怎么了？
He's old legion.
Reconnaissance. Why?
我不相信他
I don't trust him.
这很有趣，他也不相信你
That's funny, he said
the same thing about you.
拿着，换衣服
你的衣服留下来
Here. Get changed.
Your clothes stay behind.
我们去的地方不能穿高跟鞋
You won't be needing high heels
where we're going.
德克斯追踪信号到了这里
卡勒根的北方流域
Dex tracked the signal to here,
this valley north of Karakal.
这就是信号发出的地方
This is where
the transmission originated.
为什么这里没有标记呢？
这里是什么地方？
Why is there no writing here?
What is this place?
- 香巴拉
- 你知道吗？
- Shambhala.
- You know it?
这是禁地
It is forbidden.
据说是据称那里是时间之轮的发源地
一种西藏巫术
It's said to be the source
of the Kalachakra, Tibetan magic.
据说生活在那里的人有超自然的力量
Those who live there are said
to have supernatural powers.
你能带我们去那，卡吉，是吗？
You can get us there, Kaji,
can't you?
没人会冒这个险
太危险了
No one has ventured this far.
It's very dangerous.
香巴拉据说受时轮喇嘛庙的主持的保护
Shambhala is said to be protected by
the priests of the Kalachakra lamasery.
如果他们发现我们在这儿
他们会杀了我们的
If they find us there,
they will kill us.
为什么？为什么这个地方这么特别
Why? Why is this place so special?
香巴拉还有很多名字
对希伯来人来说，它是伊甸园
Shambhala is known by many names.
To the Hebrew, it is Eden.
对于古希腊人来说，它是圣域
To the ancient Greek,
it was Empurios.
你们可能听过香格里拉
You may know it as Shangri-la.
风暴要来了
如果你们仍然想去，我们现在就必须走了
A storm is coming. If you still wish
to go, we must go now.
我需要发一条信息
I need to send a message.
佩利编辑，这可能是
你收到我的最后一条信息了
Editor Paley, this may be the last
message you receive from me.
我们追踪无线信号到了尼泊尔
去寻找托滕可夫博士
We've tracked a radio signal to Nepal
in search of Dr. Totenkopf.
这个新闻越来越曲折离奇
The story grows stranger
at every turn.
关于倒计时的线索到底是什么，我不知道
Clues about a countdown.
But to what, I don't know.
我担心时间已经不够了
I fear time is running out.
如果幸运，我将很快带着德克斯
还有这个新闻一起回来
With any luck, I'll be back soon
with Dex and the story.
我希望我能成功
波莉・帕金斯
I hope. Polly Perkins.
这里是与世隔绝的地方
This is where civilization stops.
地图在这里是一片空白
A blank on the map.
从这里开始，我们必须小心
We must be careful from here.
快点
Hurry.
这是什么？
What is it?
这看起来象一个矿区
It looks like a mining outpost.
这里发生过不幸的事
Something bad happened here.
看起来已经被遗弃了
Seems to be abandoned.
告诉你的人我们往下走
Tell your men we're heading down.
我得走近去看看
I want a closer look.
那是什么，约瑟夫？
What is it, Joe?
铀
Uranium.
整个矿井都被污染了
The whole mine's contaminated.
- 我们不能呆在这里
- 快点离开
- We can't stay here.
- Let's go.
波莉呢？
Where's Polly?
波莉！
Polly!
帕金斯小姐？
Miss Perkins?
我们需要分开来找
We'll have to split up.
波莉！
Polly!
不要管她了
Let her go.
把管子给我，她才能活命
Give me the vials
and the girl will live.
什么管子？
你在说些什么啊？
What vials?
What are you talking about?
我不会再要一遍
I will not ask a second time.
把枪丢掉
Drop the gun.
我已经告诉你了，我不知道你在说些什么
等会儿你就得把我们都杀了
I told you, I don't know what you're
talking about. You'll just have to kill us.
你说得没错
As you wish.
等等！ 等等，等等
Wait! Wait. Wait.
对不起，约瑟夫
I'm sorry, Joe.
再见了，我的朋友们
你们的旅程就在这里结束了
Goodbye, my friends.
Your journey ends here.
我本来准备告诉你的，约瑟夫
你得相信我
I was going to tell you, Joe.
You have to believe me.
- 管子里面装了什么？
- 我不知道
- What was in those vials?
- I don't know.
- 你认为我会相信？
- 我说的是实话，约瑟夫
- You expect me to believe that?
- I'm telling the truth, Joe.
詹宁斯博士在他死前给我的
Dr. Jennings gave them to me
just before he died.
他说如果托滕可夫得到那个瓶子的话
He said that the world would end
and the countdown would begin
世界末日就会来临的
倒计时就会开始
if Totenkopf got his hands on them.
从一开始你就没对我说过实话
You've done nothing but lie to me
from the beginning.
是的，我没说实话，但是我没有夸大事实
詹宁斯博士就是那样讲的
Okay, I'm a liar. But I don't exaggerate.
That is what he said.
那就是托滕可夫一直在找的东西
That was what Totenkopf
was looking for.
- 也是他为什么带走德克斯的原因
- 对不起
- That's why he took Dex.
- I'm sorry.
我从没想过这些事情会发生
I never meant for any of this
to happen.
你听到那声音了吗？
Do you hear that?
炸药
Dynamite.
又是那种声音
That noise again.
快点！
Move!
你在干吗？
What are you doing?
快跑！
Come on!
哦，太好了
Oh, great.
我们安全了
We're safe.
波莉，这也许是我们呆在一起的最后时光
Polly, this may be
our last moment together.
我有些事情要问你
There's something
I need to ask you.
什么事，约瑟夫？
Yes, Joe?
你割了我的油管吗？
Did you cut my fuel line?
天啊！我没有动你那恶心的飞机！
Damn it! I didn't sabotage
your lousy airplane!
我们在世上的最后时光
你要问我的就是这个？
Our last moments on earth
and this is all you have to say to me?
我们能不能在死去时不争论这些东西？
Could we just for once die
without all this bickering?
你们在这里啊
There you are.
- 你们为什么把门锁上？
- 快跑！
- Why did you lock the door?
- Run!
我的胶卷
My film.
波莉．不要了！
没时间了！
Polly, leave it!
There's no time!
波莉
Polly.
我的衣服
My clothes.
你在这里干什么？
出去，出去！
What are you doing in here?
Get out. Get out!
除非你在下面为我藏了一条裤子
Not unless you have some pants
hidden under there for me.
- 哦，不要告诉我你是
- 光着身子
- Oh, don't tell me you're--
- Naked.
- 没错，波莉
- 这个不好笑，约瑟夫
- You can say it, Polly.
- This isn't funny, Joe.
我们在哪里？发生什么事情了？
我们的衣服呢？
Where are we? What happened to us?
Where are our clothes?
不要那样看着我
Stop looking at me like that.
怎样？
Like what?
转过身去，约瑟夫
Turn around, Joe.
我是认真的，转过身去
I'm serious. Turn around.
嘿，约瑟夫
Hi, Joe.
问他把我们的衣服怎么了
Ask him what he did
with our clothes.
衣服被烧了
The clothes are burned.
被烧了？为什么？
Burned? Why?
他说矿井是有毒的
He says the mine is poisonous.
我们的衣服被污染了
Our clothes were infected.
他说他准备带我们回到山下去
He says he's arranged for a guide
to lead us back down the mountain.
我们穿好衣服他就带我们走
He will take us there
once we are dressed.
我们对此深表谢意，但是和他说清楚
我们到这里来是为了找一个人的
We appreciate that. But explain to him
we are here to find a man.
他说我们必须在天黑前离开
He says we must leave
before it is dark.
他不能再帮我们做些什么了
There's nothing more
he can do for us.
找到这个人是件很重要的事情
It's very important we find this man.
他的名字是托滕可夫！
His name is Totenkopf!
他问，你找这个人干嘛？
He says, what do you want
with this man?
我来杀他
I've come to kill him.
还有找我的朋友
And to find my friend.
他说他会帮你
He says he will help you.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我想他们不该把衣服烧掉
I think they burned
the wrong clothes.
你和我说不能带其他的任何东西
You said I couldn't bring
anything else.
我看你像头长毛象
I think you look like
a woolly mammoth.
他们在等我们
They're waiting for us.
主持说托滕可夫压迫他的手下
The priest says that Totenkopf
enslaved his people,
让他们在有毒的矿里干活
made them work in the mine,
but the mine was poisonous.
而那些没有马上死的人
被送到这里给他研究
Those who did not die right away
were brought here for him to study.
托滕可夫现在在哪里？
Where is Totenkopf now?
他也不知道，只知道
托滕可夫在多年前走了
He does not know. Only that
Totenkopf is gone, many years ago.
我不敢相信发生的这一切
I can't believe this is happening.
底片只剩下两张了
I only have two shots left.
我们现在在香格里拉
但是我只剩下两张底片
We're in Shangri-la
and all I have is two shots.
我所有的东西都在那个包里
Everything I had was in that bag.
你该让我回去取胶卷的
You should have let me go back
for my film.
对的,我应该让你去拿
You're right, I should have.
他带我们去哪里？
So where's he taking us?
去见托滕可夫试验过后唯一的幸存者
To meet the only living survivor
of Totenkopf's experiments.
什么试验？
What experiments?
问他，托滕可夫在哪里？
告诉他找到托滕可夫很重要
Ask him, where is Totenkopf?
Tell him it's important we find him.
他想知道为什么
你为什么找托滕可夫？
He wants to know why.
Why do you seek Totenkopf?
让他为他所做过的事情后悔
To make him pay
for what he has done.
他的杖子，他在要他的杖子
His staff. He's asking for his staff.
他说，跟着罗娜
杖子会引导你们找到托滕可夫
He says, follow Rana. The staff
will lead you there to Totenkopf.
罗娜？有这个地方吗？
Rana? Is there such a place?
他说他已经帮过你了
你得帮他了
He says now that he has helped you,
you must help him.
没问题，什么都可以
Of course. Anything.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
杀了我
Kill me.
你看过这个了吗？
它上面有标记，像是一把尺子
Have you looked at this?
There's markings on it, like a ruler.
并且还有月亮和星星
And there's a moon and a star.
他告诉我开着飞机去
And all I ask is a tall ship
让星星为你导航
and a star to steer her by
一颗星星
A star.
他讲的不是地名
是一颗星星！
He wasn't talking about a place,
he was talking about a star!
罗娜是颗星星
Rana is a star.
古时的水手是靠星空来导航的
Ancient sailors used to navigate
by using the night sky.
他们通过月亮和星星来确定他们的位置
They could determine their position
by the moon and the stars.
北欧海盗就是以通过一些星星
画地图而著称
The Vikings were known
to create maps for certain stars,
北欧海盗就是以通过一些星星
画地图而著称
The Vikings were known
to create maps for certain stars,
制作纬度表也需要一颗关键的星
Iatitude tables that required a key
to decipher them.
这颗关键的星就是雅格布之星
一定就是这个东西！
The key was called Jacob's staff.
This has to be the key!
你是说这个确实可以用来导航？
You mean this could really work?
你确认可以用这个来找到托滕可夫？
You could really find Totenkopf
with this thing?
现在我们只是做起来
和古人有些不一样而已
We do things a little
different nowadays.
我们需要知道的是从哪里着手
今天几号？
All we needed to know was where
to look. What's the date?
- 三月二日
- March 2.
把卡拉卡尔高原作为我们的假定位置...
Using Karakal Plateau
as our assumed position...
三月二日...
March 2...
罗娜的纬度是20.40
Rana is at latitude 20.40.
赤经，3个赤经十五度，再43分
Right ascension, 03 hours,
43 minutes.
赤纬，减去10.60
Declination, minus 10.60.
那里什么也没有
There's nothing there.
你肯定你没搞错？
Are you sure you did it right?
当然没错
I'm sure.
如果那个老人没搞错
托滕可夫现在就应该在那里
If the old man was right,
that's where Totenkopf is now.
真是一个难以捉摸的死疙瘩啊
Dead center in the middle
of nowhere.
那个点是什么意思？
What's that point there?
我们飞到那里就没油了
That's where we run out of fuel.
哦，还真不赖
Oh, great.
那我们怎么飞到目的地？
So how do we get there?
- 弗兰基
- 谁？
- Franky.
- Who?
弗兰基・库克
我的一位老朋友
Frank Cook. An old buddy of mine.
她掌管着一支皇家海军机动侦察前哨部队
Runs a mobile reconnaissance outpost
for the Royal Navy.
如果我能和他们联系上的话
If I can get a message to them,
我也许可以安排在那个坐标会合
I may be able to arrange a rendezvous
at these coordinates.
那如果联系不上呢？
And what if they don't
get the message?
弗兰基从来没让我失望过
他们会在那里出现的
Franky's never let me down.
They'll be there.
他们肯定会到的
那盏信号灯这时候亮是不是在你预料之中？
Is that light supposed to be on?
放心，波莉，不会有事的
Relax, Polly, everything's fine.
- 飞机没油了，对吧？
- 系好安全带
- We're out of fuel, aren't we?
- Buckle up.
曼塔基地，能收到我的信息吗？
Manta Station, do you read me?
你在哪里，弗兰基？
Where are you, Franky?
你在干吗？
What are you doing?
我们不能在这个不毛之地迫降啊
You can't land this
in the middle of nowhere.
没有啊，我正准备降落在上面
I'm not. I'm landing it on that.
- 这是什么？
- 这是一个机动机场
- What is it?
- It's a mobile airstrip.
德克斯也参与了设计
Dex had a hand in designing it.
这是一个秘密
你会保密的，对吧，波莉？
It's kind of a secret. You can keep
a secret, can't you, Polly?
当然
Yeah.
我会保守秘密的
I can keep a secret.
两张底片
Two shots.
允许在327号甲板上降落
保持目前航线
Permission to land on platform 327.
Maintain your present course.
收到，327
Copy, 327.
欢迎降落，上尉
Welcome aboard, captain.
约瑟夫・苏利文
我还以为你已经死了
Joseph Sullivan.
I was sure you'd be dead by now.
很高兴见到你,弗兰基
It's good to see you too, Franky.
最好是有重要任务否则有你好受的
This had better be important
or one of us is in trouble.
是有重要任务
It's important.
那是谁？
What is that?
要友好点
You be nice.
库克指挥官
这是波莉・帕金斯
Commander Cook,
meet Polly Perkins.
波莉・帕金斯
久仰了
Polly Perkins.
I've heard so much about you.
终于遇到了我的情敌真令人高兴
It's a pleasure to finally meet
the competition.
南京的事情过去有段时间了吧
对吧，约瑟夫？
It's been a long time since Nanjing,
hasn't it, Joseph?
呃，弗兰基，我听说你的三号引擎有点问题
So, Franky, I hear you've been having
trouble with that number-three engine,
至少上次是这样的
or at least you were last time--
指挥官，我们在西北方
发现敌人的六艘潜艇
Commander, we're tracking six
enemy submersibles
方位是西北30度
bearing 30 degrees northwest.
- 现在谁想要杀你啊？
- 让你的人进入战斗位置
- Who wants to kill you now?
- Man your battle stations.
- 全体船员做好战斗准备
- 跟我来
- All hands on deck.
- Follow me.
升到10000英尺
开始反击
Take us to 1 0,000 feet
and deploy countermeasures.
遵命，长官
Yes, commander.
侦察分队在我们东北方向
Reconnaissance located an island
3公里处发现了一个小岛
3 kilometers northeast
of our current position.
但是我们无法在任何地图上找到它
It is not, however,
on any of our charts.
- 肯定就是他
- 就是谁？
- That has to be him.
- That has to be who?
这次你又让我惹上什么麻烦了，约瑟夫？
What have you got me
into this time, Joseph?
没有什么你对付不了的，弗兰基
Nothing you can't handle, Franky.
波莉，不要碰任何东西
Polly, try not to touch anything.
敌舰方位316
4号区域，正在快速靠近
Enemy warships bearing 316,
mark 4. Closing fast.
- 给我一个图像
- 发射无线电成像仪
- Give me a visual.
- Launching radio imager.
我们接收到了一个信号
正在屏幕上
We're receiving a signal.
On-screen now.
托滕可夫
Totenkopf.
长官，我们的前进马达已经不能运行了
我们正在下降
Commander, we've lost power to the
forward rotors. We're losing altitude.
所有的发动机，全速反转
让我们离开这里
All engines, reverse full.
Get us out of here.
弗兰基，你得让我去那个岛
Francesca, you've got to get me
on that island.
我可不想为了你的愚蠢行为
拿我手下人的生命做赌注
I'm not about to risk the lives
of my men for one of your silly antics.
他抓了德克斯
He's got Dex.
取消命令！
Rescind order!
从空中你永远都没办法
我们得另辟蹊径
You'll never make it from the air.
We have to find you another way.
在岛的东面有潮汐涌动
There's a tidal flow on the eastern face
of the island.
太深了
我们不能下潜超过300米
It's too deep.
We're not rated past 300 meters.
但是...
But...
...这块区域
...this area here,
在南端有个海底入口
there's an undersea inlet
at the southern tip
它穿越了整个岛屿
这是你唯一的路径
and it runs beneath the entire length
of the island. That is your only way in.
其他的岛岸都是岩石
Everything else is sheer rock
to the edge of the water.
那这些机器人怎么办？
我们怎么通过？
What about those machines?
How do we get past them?
这个问题我来解决
Leave that to me.
通知两栖机组做好战斗准备
Alert the amphibious squadron.
前往母舰做好战斗准备
Report to main station carrier.
什么？
What?
南京？
Nanjing?
我听不清你在说什么,波莉
I can't hear you, Polly.
你得说大声点
You'll have to speak up.
保持机头向上，约瑟夫
你的短程起飞总是很差
Keep your nose up, Joseph. You
always were bad at the short takeoff.
小心，弗兰基
我可不想回来帮你
Keep up, Franky. I don't wanna
have to come back for you.
我认为你刚才的起飞很棒
I thought your takeoff was just fine.
谢谢，波莉
Thank you, Polly.
那你刚才听见了，没错吧？
So you heard that, did you?
曼塔队长呼叫曼塔机组
10秒后入水
Manta leader to Manta team,
impact in ten seconds.
切换到两栖模式
Switching to amphibious mode.
入水倒计时开始5，4，3
Impact in five, four, three,
2，1
two, one.
弗兰基
Franky.
你还记得我们在上海的勤务飞行
没忘记吧？
You remember our milk run
over Shanghai, don't you?
我们锁定了目标但是他被高射炮火击中了
We had the target buttoned up
and he was jinxing in the flak.
- 一颗铆钉砰地跳出来,以为他被击中了
- 然后开始大叫:
- Pops a rivet, thinks he's taken a hit.
- And started yelling:
- 保护长机！
- "Protect the rabbits!
- Protect the rabbits!"
敌人目标出现在右方四点处
深度1600，小心
Enemy target spotted four points
to the right. Depth, 1,600. Look sharp.
约瑟夫，小心！
Joe, watch out!
- 约瑟夫，入口在那里
- 我看见了
- Joseph, there's the inlet.
- I see it.
准备好冲进去
我们会为你清除路障
Get ready to make a run for it.
We're about to clear you a path.
抓牢了，波莉
抓住
Hold on, now, Polly.
Hold on.
曼塔队长呼叫曼塔机组
Manta leader to Manta team,
准备发射集束鱼雷
瞄准中心部分
arm cluster torpedoes
and stick close to element formation.
发射
Fire.
约瑟夫！拉起来！
Joseph! Pull up!
约瑟夫，它还活着，快离开
Joseph, it's still alive. Disengage.
收到了吗？快离开
Do you hear me? Disengage.
收到了吗？
Do you hear me?
- 这是什么？
- 收到了吗？拉起来！
- What is it?
- Do you hear me? Pull up!
- 舵被卡住了，我无法控制方向
- 约瑟夫！
- The rudder's jammed. I can't steer.
- Joseph!
快离开！
Disengage!
- 谢谢你，弗兰基，刚刚差点被击中
- 准备好冲刺
- Thank you, Franky. That was close.
- Get ready to make a run for it.
准备好给他点颜色看看
You're only going to have
one shot at this.
弗兰基，你在干吗？
现在不是炫耀你技术的时候
Franky, what are you doing?
This is no time to show off.
- 她朝着它笔直飞过去了
- 没错
- She's heading straight for it.
- On my mark.
- 她准备撞它了
- 这是自杀啊
- She's going to ram it.
- It's suicide.
弗兰基,拉起来
Franky, pull up.
- 3
- 拉起来，弗兰基
- Three.
- Pull up, Franky.
路障清除完毕
You're all clear.
祝你好运，约瑟夫
Good luck, Joe.
谢谢你，弗兰基
接下来该我们表演了
Thank you, Franky.
We'll take it from here.
她真棒
She's some kind of girl.
是的，我知道
Yes, I know.
我们正在上升
I'm taking us up.
什么？
What?
- 这是什么？
- 托滕可夫创造的生物之一
- What is it?
- One of Totenkopf's creatures.
- 你不准备拍它吗？
- 我只剩下两张底片了
- You're not gonna photograph that?
- I've only got two shots left.
鬼知道等会儿还会有什么东西
Who knows what's waiting for us
out there.
随你的便
Suit yourself.
前面有清理过的痕迹
托滕可夫就在附近
There's a clearing up ahead.
Totenkopf can't be far.
快跑
Run.
那边
There.
波莉！
Polly!
哦，还真不赖
Oh, great.
快跑！
Come on!
波莉！
Polly!
快点！
Come on!
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
你是不是疯了？
你脑子是不是有毛病？
刚才你差点就害得自己被杀掉了！
Are you completely insane?
You could have gotten yourself killed!
- 算了算了
- 哦，没关系
- It's okay.
- No, it isn't.
- 我的意思不是
- 我刚才拍的是地面！
- I didn't mean--
- I shot the ground!
- 什么？
- 当我们在逃跑的时候
- What?
- When we were running,
我拍了地面
I shot the ground.
这个一点也不好笑
It isn't funny.
我只剩下一张底片了
一张！
I only have one shot left.
One shot!
那个鬼相机对你来说有什么意义？
What is it with you
and that stupid camera, anyway?
是你送给我的
You gave it to me.
连你自己也不记得了？
You don't even remember, do you?
当你和美国志愿者在南京开着飞机的时候
You were flying with the American
volunteers in Nanjing,
我正在报道上海的撤退
I was covering the evacuation
of Shanghai.
- 我记得的
- 约瑟夫，我想问你几个问题
- I remember.
- Joe, I wanna ask you something
你得老实回答我的问题
and I want you to tell me the truth.
我发誓我不在乎答案是什么
我只是想知道真相
I don't care one way or the other,
I swear. I just need to know.
你在南京的女友是弗兰基
对吗？
The girl in Nanjing was Franky,
wasn't it?
- 波莉
- 你和她在一起呆了多久？
- Polly.
- How long were you seeing her?
看着我的眼睛
Look me in the eyes.
我从来没有让你戴过绿帽子
I never fooled around on you.
从来没有
Never.
是我破坏了你的飞机
I sabotaged your plane.
- 三个月
- 我就知道！
- Three months.
- I knew it!
我不敢想象我怎么才能相信你
你这个可恶的
I can't believe I ever trusted you,
you lousy--
他在这里
He's here.
你没事吧？
You all right?
从这里走
Through there.
我的天啊，约瑟夫
My God, Joe.
是诺亚方舟
It's an ark.
他在建一个诺亚方舟
He's building an ark.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
你认为还有比把地球上所有的
You honestly think you're gonna
find something more important
生物成双成对的
放在这个巨大的火箭船里面
than every single creature on Earth
being led two by two
更为壮观的场景吗？
inside a giant rocket ship?
我也许还能发现更壮观的
I might.
- 比如说？
- 当我看见的时候就知道了
- Like what?
- I'll know when I see it.
- 离起飞还有10分钟
- 他们开始倒计时了
- Ten minutes to liftoff.
- They've started the countdown.
我们得找到托滕可夫
We have to find Totenkopf.
这下你中奖了
You've got a gift.
- 德克斯！
- 快点，进来！
- Dex!
- Hurry, get in!
上来
科姆，快走！
Einsteigen. Komm, springt!
你们都还好吧？
你怎么找到我们的？
Are you all right?
How did you find us?
倒计时开始的时候我们逃进了隧道
We escaped into the tunnels
once the countdown started.
还有一些科学家没能逃出来
Some of the scientists were caught.
They didn't make it.
看守我们的那些机器人
The machines that were guarding us
正在把这个岛上的所有东西装上船
are loading everything on this island
into that ship.
我们只有大约十分钟时间来阻止
飞船点火起飞
We've got about ten minutes
to stop that thing from blasting off.
德克斯！ 带我们离开这里！
Dex! Get us out of here!
干得好，德克斯
Good boy, Dex.
谢谢，上尉
Thanks, Cap.
- 他们是谁？
- 他们是11单元
- Who are they?
- They're Unit 1 1.
也可以说是11单元的幸存者
Or what's left of them.
他们被带到这里完成一个30年前的计划
They were brought here to finish
what they started 30 years ago.
完成什么？
Finish what?
告诉他们
Tell them.
托滕可夫认为人类注定要灭亡
Totenkopf believed that humankind
was doomed to extinction,
所以他不可思议的提出了：
so he proposed the unthinkable:
建造一个装置把另外一个文明所需的
基础单元
To build a vessel that would carry
the building blocks of a new civilization
送入太空
into space.
他利用他的机器人
He used his machines
to collect specimens
把地球上的所有物种放在一起
representing all life on Earth.
托滕可夫称之为“明日帝国”
What Totenkopf called
"The World of Tomorrow."
詹宁斯博士给我的那些管子是什么？
Those vials that Dr. Jennings
gave me, what were they?
亚当和夏娃
托滕可夫的杰作
Adam and Eve.
Totenkopf's masterpiece.
科技乌托邦的星星之火
Seeds of a technological utopia.
我们偷偷的把他们带出了这个小岛
We smuggled them off this island,
因为我们知道托滕可夫没有他们
是不会离开的
knowing Totenkopf
would never leave without them.
但是现在他再次得到了他们
没有任何东西可以把他留在这里了
But now that he has them again,
there is nothing left to keep him here.
既然这样让他走好了
在太空他也不能伤害任何人
Then let him go. Let him go
where he can't harm anyone.
不行，那艘船永远都不能离开地球
No, no, no, that ship
must never leave this Earth.
为什么？你还有什么没有告诉我们？
Why? What haven't you told us?
当飞船到达100公里高度的太空边缘时
When the rocket reaches 100
kilometers, at the edge of space,
- 地球会被毁灭掉的
- 我们怎么阻止它？
- Earth will be incinerated.
- How do we stop it?
现在只有托滕可夫可以阻止它
但是我们永远都无法靠近他
Only Totenkopf can stop it now. But
we've never been allowed near him.
他的防卫措施很好，见他的面都很困难
He's too well guarded
even to be seen.
- 他在哪里？
- 我们正在去找他，上尉
- Where is he?
- We're on our way, Cap.
干得好，德克斯
Good boy, Dex.
小心，小心
Careful. Careful.
快点，他们会来追我们的
Hurry, they'll be coming for us.
从那里走
那是唯一的途径
Through there.
That's the only way in.
你们都看见没有其他的路了
You see, there is no way past them.
只有5分钟了，约瑟夫
Five minutes, Joe.
- 在这里等我
- 你会死的
- Wait here.
- You'll be killed.
他知道自己在干什么
He knows what he's doing.
我想
I think.
嘿，那是我的枪！
Hey, that's my gun!
- 德克斯？
- 试着摇一摇
- Dex?
- Try shaking it.
- 我们得快点
- 不要过去，白痴！
- We must hurry.
- Don't do it, you idiot!
博士，不要过去！
Doctor, stop!
谁这么大胆到我这里来了？
Who dares come before me?
谁竟然胆敢进到这里来了？
Who dares enter this place?
已经开始的就无法结束
What has begun
cannot be stopped.
- 是时候结束这个万恶的世界了
- 托滕可夫
- The time for this world is over.
- T otenkopf.
嘿，博士
Hello, doctor.
你为什么这样做？
Why are you doing this?
我见证了一个充满了憎恨的世界
I have been witness to a world
consumed by hatred
不断走向自我的灭亡
and bent on self-destruction.
我们作为这个星球的一员却不负责任
Watched as we have taken
what was to be a paradise
导致这个往日的天堂在不断堕落
and failed in our responsibilities
as its steward.
我很清楚人类为自己设定的轨迹
I know now that the course
the human race has set for itself
是无法改变的
cannot be changed.
我是这个注定要灭亡的星球的最后希望
I am the last, desperate chance
for a doomed planet.
现在，不离开这里就是死路一条！
Now, leave this place or die!
- 现在安全吗？
- 呃，只有一个办法来确认了
- Is it safe?
- Well, there's only one way to find out.
我的意思是丢点东西上去
I meant throw something.
他不在这里
He's not here.
我们来晚了
We're too late.
这些是他的私人文件
These are his personal papers.
他不会丢下这些东西的
他一定还在这里
He would never leave without them.
He must still be here.
- 我们得找到他
- 我找到他了
- We must find him.
- I found him.
不可能是这样得
It's impossible.
不能这样
It can't be.
他日记上的最后一次记录是在
10月11日，1918
The last entry in his journal
was made on October 1 1, 1 91 8.
他20年前就死了
He died over 20 years ago.
我们一直在寻找一个幽灵
We've been chasing a ghost.
还有3分钟时间起飞
Three minutes to liftoff.
没有办法阻止他们了
他们正在按照程序完成整个计划
They never stopped. They're finishing
what they were programmed to do.
你难道没看见？整个岛就是托滕可夫
每根管线，每套设备
Don't you see? This entire island
is Totenkopf. Every wire, every gear.
连他的死也是在欺骗我们
He's found a way to cheat
even his own death.
我们怎么杀死一个已经死了的人？
So how do we kill somebody
who's already dead?
- 我怎样才能阻止它？
- 现在没有任何东西能够阻止它了
- How do I stop it?
- Nothing can stop it now.
- 一定有什么办法
- 他的机器人不会允许你这么做的
- There must be some way.
- His machines would never allow it.
我来解决这些机器人
德克斯，告诉我怎么做
Leave the machines to me.
Dex, show me what to do.
如果你切断系统终端的导航部分
If you can cut the lead
in the system terminal,
会引起短路...
it should create a short...
可以在助推发动机点火前
点燃燃料管线
...which will ignite the fuel line
before the booster engines can fire
- 来破坏发动机点火的气氛
- 就这样？
- and destroy the atmosphere.
- That's it?
- 这就是我所要做的？
- 但是终端在飞船上面
- That's all I have to do?
- The terminal's onboard the rocket.
你将没有时间逃离
You won't have time to escape.
你们离开这个岛后
马上和弗兰基取得联系
Contact Franky as soon
as you're off the island.
- 她知道该怎么办
- 你们在讲些什么？
- She'll know exactly what to do.
- What are you talking about?
- 我要和你一起去
- 这次不行
- I'm going with you.
- Not this time.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
你不能在事情变得有趣的时候离开我
You're not gonna leave me now,
just when things are getting interesting.
- 我不会让你一个人走的
- 我希望我们要是有更多时间就好了
- I won't let you.
- I wish we had more time.
现在我只是希望，有那么一天
你能原谅我
And I only hope, one day,
you can forgive me.
- 照顾好她，德克斯
- 祝你好运，上尉
- Take care of her, Dex.
- Good luck, Cap.
一分钟后起飞
One minute to liftoff.
我们又见面了
我神秘的朋友
We meet again,
my mysterious friend.
你要怎么样？
How do you wanna do this?
干得好,波莉
Nice shot, Polly.
你怎么这么久才来？
What took you so long?
她是机器人
She's a machine.
10秒后起飞
Ten seconds to liftoff.
我们得把这些动物弄下飞船
We've gotta get those animals
off the ship.
90公里后发动机点火
Ninety kilometers to booster ignition.
没时间了
There's no time.
这是我们过去的唯一途径
That's our only way across.
80公里后发动机点火
Eighty kilometers to booster ignition.
危险！危险！危险！
飞船货物即将卸下！
Danger! Danger! Danger!
Cargo release imminent!
你刚才做什么了？
What did you do now?
快来！
Come on!
70公里后发动机点火
Seventy kilometers to booster ignition.
60公里后发动机点火
Sixty kilometers to booster ignition.
抓牢！
Hold on!
天啊！不要再碰任何东西了！
Please! Don't touch anything else!
没时间了，我们无法阻止它了
There's no time. We'll never make it.
50公里后发动机点火
Fifty kilometers to booster ignition.
快跑！
Run!
40公里后发动机点火
Forty kilometers to booster ignition.
请求进入，曼塔基地
你收到我的消息了吗？
Come in, Manta station.
Do you read me?
30公里后发动机点火
Thirty kilometers to booster ignition.
弗兰基，我是德克斯
你能收到我的消息吗？
Franky, it's Dex. Do you read me?
这样没用
It didn't work.
20公里后发动机点火
Twenty kilometers to booster ignition.
约瑟夫，你没时间了
你得想点办法
Joe, you're running out of time.
You've gotta do something.
上帝看见地球上恶人横行
And God saw that the wickedness
of man was great in the earth...
- 他以为自己是上帝
- 上帝告诉诺亚，末日...
- He thinks he's God.
- And God said unto Noah, the end...
住嘴！
Shut up!
10公里后发动机点火
Ten kilometers to booster ignition.
- 6
- 你怎么还不去死？
-...six...
- Why won't you die?
5公里后发动机点火
Five kilometers to booster ignition.
警告，系统故障
Warning. System failure.
发动机故障
Booster malfunction.
危险，危险
Danger. Danger.
危险
Danger.
警告，系统故障
Warning. System failure.
- 发动机故障
- 小心！
- Booster malfunction.
- Look!
危险，危险
Danger. Danger.
- 这是什么？
- 也许是我们的逃生之路
- What is it?
- It might be our way out of here.
我看见他们了，长官
I see them, commander.
攻击分队预备
所有船员做好准备
Ready assault teams.
All hands on deck.
最后一张
One shot.
你得到了你的新闻了
You got your story.
波莉
Polly.
- 你...
- 没关系
- You...
- It's all right.
你不需要说什么
You don't have to say anything.
你的相机盖没有开
Lens cap.